Speaker 1: Donald Trump wants to end birthright citizenship.
Speaker 1: Left-wing media and Democrats are fighting it tooth and nail
Speaker 1: because illegals, indeed criminals, are their mother's milk.
Speaker 1: Among Donald Trump's first avalanche of executive orders
Speaker 1: was one ending birthright citizenship,
Speaker 1: the policy where almost anybody born on U.S. soil
Speaker 1: automatically gets citizenship.
Speaker 1: The practice itself comes from a misreading of the 14th Amendment,
Speaker 1: which granted citizenship to freed slaves,
Speaker 1: specifically to, quote,
Speaker 1: all persons born in the United States
Speaker 1: and subject to the jurisdiction thereof.
Speaker 1: The key phrase here is subject to the jurisdiction.
Speaker 1: That's long been understood to exclude diplomats,
Speaker 1: so birth alone is not enough,
Speaker 1: but jurisdiction is actually a whole lot more limiting.
Speaker 1: Historian Tom Wood cites the authors of the 14th Amendment,
Speaker 1: who said, quote,
Speaker 1: this will not, of course, include persons born in the United States
Speaker 1: who are foreigners or aliens,
Speaker 1: because it only applies to people, quote,
Speaker 1: not owing allegiance to any foreign sovereignty.
Speaker 1: In other words, if you have citizenship of another country, say Mexico,
Speaker 1: you are not under the jurisdiction, according to the 14th.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Because the point of the 14th was to give citizenship to former slaves
Speaker 1: who held no other citizenship.
Speaker 1: Now, notably, for 50 years after the 14th,
Speaker 1: Indians were not given birthright citizenship,
Speaker 1: specifically because they were citizens of another nation,
Speaker 1: the Navajo, Comanche, Seminole.
Speaker 1: And when they were given birthright citizenship,
Speaker 1: it was by act of Congress, not the 14th.
Speaker 1: Of course, not only are legal subject to the jurisdiction of another country,
Speaker 1: they are in this country illegally.
Speaker 1: They are literally fugitives from the law,
Speaker 1: the very definition of not under the jurisdiction.
Speaker 1: Now, this all matters because so-called birthright citizenship
Speaker 1: is one of the most abused parts of our immigration system.
Speaker 1: Every year, roughly 622,000 people are born to non-citizen parents,
Speaker 1: of which 400,000 to illegals.
Speaker 1: That comes to one in six births in the country.
Speaker 1: In the case of illegals, anchor babies become a jackpot.
Speaker 1: One study found 75% of migrants from Guatemala and Mexico with children
Speaker 1: are on federal welfare programs,
Speaker 1: adding up to hundreds of billions in costs.
Speaker 1: Indeed, we've heard stories from Biden's illegals
Speaker 1: where young women in shelters try to get knocked up
Speaker 1: by pretty much anybody to get that precious anchor baby,
Speaker 1: your tax dollars at work.
Speaker 1: The abuse extends to an estimated 40,000 so-called birth tourists
Speaker 1: who literally fly to America on vacation,
Speaker 1: give birth, and go home with the status of parents of an American citizen
Speaker 1: despite having spent mere days in the country.
Speaker 1: This is a full-on industry in China and Taiwan
Speaker 1: where pre-birthing centers are common,
Speaker 1: kind of an assisted care for pregnant women.
Speaker 1: But instead of doing it in China,
Speaker 1: they fly to a center in LA,
Speaker 1: fully staffed by Chinese,
Speaker 1: and presto, they get all the benefits of citizenship.
Speaker 1: All in between the illegals, temporary visas like H-1Bs or students
Speaker 1: and birth tourists,
Speaker 1: one in six new Americans either should not be here
Speaker 1: or have almost no connection to the country.
Speaker 1: So it's next, brought to you by Unchain.com.
Speaker 1: The left will go to war on this because they know
Speaker 1: the vast majority of beneficiaries will vote left.
Speaker 1: The case they'll keep citing is Wong Kim Ark from 1873,
Speaker 1: which grants citizenship to the child of permanent residence,
Speaker 1: something most Americans are probably fine with
Speaker 1: and something that has nothing to do
Speaker 1: with these 622,000 illegals and tourists abusing the system.
Speaker 1: Okay, we'll be watching.
Speaker 1: See you next time.